September 18, 1931. Japan, in search of raw materials with
to feed its growing industry, invades Manchuria,
an area in northeast China known for its rich mineral and coal reserves.
In the following years there will be several "incidents", or confrontations
short-range weapons, between the Empire of the Rising Sun and the Republic of China,
but a full-scale war between the two countries will not break out until the Incident of
Marco Polo Bridge, July 7, 1937. This marks the beginning of World War II.
Sino-Japanese War that only ended with Japan's surrender on September 2, 1945.
During this war, a prelude to World War II in the Pacific,
The Japanese army achieves important victories, capturing Beijing and Shanghai.
In December 1937, the Japanese army invaded Nanjing, then the capital of China.
In Nanjing, Japanese soldiers commit unspeakable atrocities
and embark on a campaign of mass murder that, over the course of two months,
It will claim the lives of up to 300,000 civilians and numerous unarmed Chinese soldiers.
However, the crimes committed by the Japanese military are not limited only to
to the said two-month period, as numerous atrocities were reported as
that the army was advancing from Shanghai to Nanjing. The most notorious of these cruelties
It is an infamous contest between two Japanese army officers over who could decapitate a
100 people are faster with their swords. Their names are Toshiaki Mukai and Tsuyoshi Noda.
The conflict in Asia between Japan and China began with the invasion of Manchuria,
long before the official start of World War II.
As part of previous treaty agreements, the Japanese had troops
protecting the railway in southern Manchuria. However, Japan wanted to expand its
control over Chinese Manchuria, so on September 18, 1931, the Japanese placed a
small explosive device next to the tracks of the Japanese South Manchuria Railway,
near the town of Mukden. The ensuing explosion became known as the
Mukden. Although the damage to the railway was minimal, it served as an excuse for the
Japanese for the rapid and unauthorized capture of the city, present-day Shenyang, and to seize
all localities located along the railway. Despite Chinese opposition,
The Japanese continued to advance and on February 27, 1932, the last Chinese who opposed
to the invasion were forced to surrender. All of Manchuria was in Japanese hands. Few
Days later, on March 1, the Japanese established the puppet state of Manchukuo,
which was not dissolved until August 18, 1945, after the Japanese Emperor Hirohito
announced the unconditional surrender of the Japanese army three days earlier.
Since the invasion of Manchuria, there have been several "incidents", or armed clashes
limited in time between the Empire of Japan and the Republic of China, but all had subsided.
However, this changed on the night of July 7, 1937, when a small Japanese force
maneuvers near the Marco Polo Bridge required entry into the small walled city of Wanping
to look for one of his soldiers. However, the city's Chinese garrison denied entry to
the Japanese; then a shot was heard and both sides began to attack. The Chinese government,
Under strong anti-Japanese pressure, he refused to make any concessions in negotiating the dispute;
The Japanese also maintained their stance. As a result, the conflict continued to escalate,
with greater forces committed by both sides and the fighting
spread to other parts of China. After the Marco Polo Bridge Incident,
which marked the beginning of the Second Sino-Japanese War or War of Resistance against
the Japanese Aggression between 1937-1945, the Japanese obtained important victories,
capturing Beijing, Shanghai and the Chinese capital of Nanjing in 1937. The latter resulted in
to a massacre in this city, also known as the Rape of Nanjing.
The Battle of Shanghai, which lasted from August 13, 1937 to November 26,
of the same year, was one of the largest and bloodiest of the entire war. Later it was
described as "Stalingrad on the Yangtze" and is often considered the battle in which
World War II truly began. After more than three months of intense ground fighting,
sea and air, the confrontation ended with the victory of Japan.
The battle can be divided into three stages, and almost a million people participated in it.
of soldiers. The first stage lasted from August 13 to 22, 1937, during which the Army
The National Revolutionary Army of the Republic of China attempted to eradicate the presence
of Japanese troops in central Shanghai. The second stage extended from August 23
to October 26, 1937, during which the Japanese launched amphibious landings in the
Jiangsu coast. The two armies fought a house-to-house battle similar to that of Stalingrad,
in which the Japanese attempted to take control of the city and surrounding regions.
The last stage, between October 27 and the end of November of that same year,
It consisted of the withdrawal of the Chinese army in the face of flanking maneuvers
Japanese and the ensuing battle on the road to China's capital, Nanjing.
Japanese General Iwane Matsui, who expelled the Chinese troops
from Shanghai and had under his command the 10th Army with which he would capture Nanjing,
He made it clear to his superiors that he was determined to take over the capital of China,
located 300 kilometers west of Shanghai. Matsui stated emphatically that
The war with China would not end until Nanjing was under its control,
and predicted that the fall of the city would lead to the total collapse of Chiang Kai-shek's government.
Although the massacre is generally described as a six-week period following the fall of Nanjing,
The crimes committed by the Japanese army were not limited to that period. According to reports,
Many atrocities were committed as the Japanese army advanced from Shanghai to Nanjing.
Perhaps the most notorious atrocity was a killing contest between two Japanese officers, Toshiaki
Mukai and Tsuyoshi Noda, both born in 1912. The contest consisted of a race to see
who first beheaded 100 people using only a sword. He was covered
as a sporting event in the Japanese press, with regular updates
of the results in four articles from November 30 to December 13, 1937.
On December 2 of the same year, five days ahead of schedule, the Japanese captured
Danyang. To achieve such agility, the Japanese soldiers carried little with them,
except for weapons and ammunition. As they marched far ahead of most of their lines of
supplies, they had to buy or loot their food from the Chinese civilians they found
along the way. One of the reasons why the 10th Army was advancing towards
Nanjing was fairly quickly due to tacit consent among the officials
and Japanese soldiers so they could pillage and rape at will. And so they did.
By then, Mukai had killed 89 people and Noda 78.
On December 13, 1937, the 6th and 116th divisions of the Japanese Army
They were the first to enter Nanjing, facing little military resistance.
From that day on, the Japanese army, including Second Lieutenant Toshiaki Mukai
and Tsuyoshi Noda, committed random murders, war rape, looting,
arson and other war crimes. They hunted down and killed
alleged Chinese soldiers and summarily arrested thousands of young people. Many
Innocent men were wrongly identified and killed in the process.
Thousands were taken to the Yangtze River, where they were machine-gunned to death. Many
Chinese soldiers blew them up with landmines, then sprayed them with
gasoline and set them on fire; those who survived were killed with bayonets.
Japanese soldiers also beheaded several Chinese prisoners of war.
The invading forces also massacred families living outside the Zone of
Security and raped tens of thousands of women. In one case, a Chinese woman,
Mrs. Ha asked the Japanese soldiers why they had killed her husband. Before
They also killed her and her baby by stabbing them in the chest with a bayonet, shot her, and raped her.
The number of Chinese women raped by Japanese soldiers ranged from 20,000 to 80,000, including
some children and the elderly. Thus, a large number of abuses were systematically committed by the
Japanese soldiers when they went door to door looking for girls and women, whom they captured
and gang-raped. They were often immediately killed by severe mutilation.
A former Japanese soldier named Shiro Azuma spoke candidly about the process of rape and
Nanjing murder: "Nothing would happen if we just raped them. I shouldn't say it was okay either.
But we always stabbed and killed them. Because corpses don't talk."
After being raped by Japanese soldiers,
The victims were often photographed. There are also accounts from Japanese troops
that coerced families to commit incestuous acts. Children were forced to
rape their mothers, fathers to abuse their daughters and brothers to do the same
with her sisters. Instead of punishing the Japanese troops responsible for
wholesale rapes, the Japanese expeditionary force in Central China
issued the order to establish houses of comfort during this period of time.
The Japanese army also looted the city and burned many buildings,
One third of the city was destroyed as a result of these arsons.
These crimes lasted from three to six weeks, depending on the type of crime.
When the Japanese army entered the city on December 13, 1937,
The reporters who caught up with Mukai and Noda did not report on the massacres committed by the
Japanese, but noted that both men - Mukai and Noda - had already surpassed their goal.
According to an article by journalists on the same December 13, Tsuyoshi Noda had killed
105 people, while Toshiaki Mukai had killed 106. However,
Since the two did not know who had been the first to reach the milestone of 100,
With the permission of their superior officer, they decided to continue their competition to see who would arrive
first at 150 kills. The newspaper headline was "Incredible record in the contest"
of beheading 100 people: Mukai 106 and Noda 105. Both second lieutenants are going to the extension."
During the interview, Mukai was apparently a little upset about
some damage to his sword, and justified it by stating that he was
spoiled “because I sliced someone in half, along with their helmet.”
What Mukai and Noda failed to mention was that,
In reality, they were largely killing defenseless prisoners and
that their victims did not perish in combat, but were murdered in cold blood.
Noda would later say the following: "Actually, I didn't kill more than four
or five people in hand-to-hand combat. We were facing an enemy trench that we had
captured, and when we shouted "Ni, Lai-Lai!", which means "You, come!", the Chinese soldiers
They were so stupid that they would rush at us all at once. Then we would put them
in a row and we would knock them down, from one end of the line to the other. I was praised for having killed a
hundreds of people, but in reality, almost all of them died this way. We had that
a contest that I was often asked if it was that big of a deal. I've always said it wasn't."
Up to 300,000 civilians and numerous unarmed Chinese soldiers were killed in the
The course of two months during the Battle of Nanjing. The chaos, the fires, and the mass graves
commons make an accurate count of casualties impossible. The violence subsided in February 1938,
after the establishment of a Chinese-led government under Japanese influence.
After the war, a written record of the conflict came to the Tribunal documents.
International Military for the Far East and, in 1947, both Mukai and Noda were
arrested by the US military and held in Sugamo Prison,
in Tokyo. They were later extradited to China and tried by the Criminal Tribunal
Nanjing War Memorial. Gunkichi Tanaka, a captain in the Japanese army who was tried alongside them, was also tried.
He personally killed with his sword more than 300 prisoners of war and civilians
Chinese during the Nanjing Massacre. The three men were found guilty
of the atrocities committed during the Battle of Nanjing and its subsequent massacre,
were sentenced to death. On January 28, 1948, Mukai,
Noda and Tanaka were executed by firing squad. Mukai and Noda were 35 years old, while Tanaka was 42.
During their trial, neither Mukai nor Noda publicly denied having participated in what was
described by a Japanese newspaper in 1937 as a "friendly contest." However,
In 2003, the families of Mukai and Noda sued the authors of the stories that described
the contest for the murder of one hundred men for being based on false statements,
requesting compensation of $300,000. Two years later, in 2005,
The Tokyo District Court ruled that "the contest took place and that it was not
an intentional invention of the media."
No se derramaron lágrimas por Toshiaki Mukai y Tsuyoshi Noda.
Thanks for watching World History Channel don't forget to give me a thumbs up
like to subscribe and click on the notification bell to
Don't miss our next videos thanks See you next time on the
canal